## Julián Lopez Baasch

{Computer Scientist, Economist} Av. Libertador 5386, Buenos Aires, Argentina +54-911-6267-7072julianlopezba@gmail.com

## PRINCIPAL INTERESTS

My research interests lie at the intersection of economics and machine learning. More specifically, I am interested in understanding how learning works in humans and how to make it feasible for agents to exploit the problems of adaptation that arise in multiagent systems. Thus, I found in agent-based computational economics and MARL methods a natural fit for my interests.

### **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

M.Sc. Intelligent Systems

2019

AIML GROUP, Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona, Spain

- Research in Multi Agent Reinforcement Learning under direction of prof. Martí Sànchez-Fibla.
- Dissertation title: Estimating loss aversion in human behavioral data: A Bayesian approach using Reinforcement Learning.
- Coursework: Machine Learning, Autonomous Systems, Pattern Recognition, Natural Language Interaction, Computer Vision, Web Intelligence, Data Driven Social Network Analysis

M.Sc. Economics 2014

Universidad Torcuato Di Tella, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Focus areas: Numerical Methods and Game Theory.
- Research in quantitative finance under direction of prof. Nicolás Merener.
- Coursework: Real Analysis, Measure Theory, Dynamic Programming, Evolutionary Game Theory, Causal Inference, Social and Economic Networks, Stochastic Calculus applied to Finance

Licenciate in Economics

2011

Universidad Torcuato Di Tella, Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Machine learning consulting for fintech startup

• Minor in Mathematics and Satistics.

# **HISTORY**

EMPLOYMENT Machine Learning Consultant

2019 - Present

- mGrana, Buenos Aires, Argentina
  - Assisting in the feature engineering and integration of features into the machine learning pipeline.
  - Built a NLP based clustering model of mobile texts data points.

Sr. Data Scienitst

2019 - Present

Banco galicia, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Building a data science team with the goal of designing, executing and delivering data products using company data and third-party sources.
- Trained and deployed NLP models for multiclass and multilabel classification of comments and posts in social networks (Twitter, Instagram and Facebook).
- Generate and track social listening metrics.

Data Analyst 2014 - 2017

### DIRECTV Latin America, Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Responsible for implementing analytical solutions to various datadriven problems related to Customer Experience regional office.

- Developed a model for measuring repeated TV content between channels based on Jaccard Index.
- Implemented a predictive model of prepaid recharges based on media, sports and social events.
- Deployed a logistic regression model to predict the level of satisfaction based on the customer journey records.

## TEACHING (at Universidad Di Tella)

• Undergrad TA in Law and Economics
Prepared text materials for 'Law and Economics' course, BS in Economics.
Helped +30 students gain a better understanding of the practical exercises and theory. Assisted group study in the problem sets solving.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages
  Python, Pytorch, TensorFlow Keras
- Framework Flask, Docker
- Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, Hadoop, Hive, Spark
- Other SNAP, Networkx, Matlab, OpenCV, javascript